

AKIS GAZEPIDIS

DATA SCIENTIST

PROFILE

Data Scientist with experience in information extraction techniques used on documents, building ETL pipelines and training of machine learning models. My passion is to accelerate internal company processes with custom made cloud applications wich lead to datadriven decisions.

CONTACT



+30 6986777430



akisgazepidis@gmail.com



Peristeri, Athens, 12137, Greece



<u>LinkedIn Profile</u>



Personal Portfolio



Google Certifications Profile



Microsoft Certifications Profile

HARD SKILLS

- Python
- Snowflake
- Azure Devops
- PostgreSQL
- Azure SQL server
- PowerBi
- Git
- Postman
- Docker
- CI/CD
- MongoDB
- Databricks

EXPERIENCE

DATA ENGINEERING CONSULTANT

D-ONE

Apr 2023- Present

- Use ETL pipelines to extract, transform, and load data from various sources.
- Build, test and deploy tables into Snowflake database.
- · Query data from Rest APIs and create collections.

Project: Database Integration projects between systems like Snowflake, Azure SQL SDerver, Databricks

DATA SCIENTIST

Generali

Jan 2022- Apr 2023

- Integrate Bitbucket version control system in development.
- Consolidate data with the use of APIs.
- Integrate OCR, Machine Vision & Machine Learning fields to automated processes.

DATA SCIENTIST

<u>Purposeful</u>

Nov 2021 - Dec 2021

- Collect publication patents through Google's BigQuery.
- Analyze texts with Natural Language Process (NLP).
- Conduct topic modeling using Latent Dirichlet Allocation. (LDA)

Project: Build a probabilistic model so as to analyze patents texts.

SOFT SKILLS

- Problem Solving
- Critical Thinking
- Adaptability
- Team Working

LANGUAGES

Greek - Native

English - ILTES 6.5

PORTFOLIO

Optimization of Titan's Mill

Deep Learning - loan prediction

Classcentral scraper

Image Handwritting Recognition

NLP - Climate Change IR System

JUNIOR DATA SCIENTIST

Big Blue Data Academy

Apr 2021 - Aug 2021

- · Web scraping with Beautiful Soup, Requests & Selenium.
- Consolidate various data sources using Pandas & JSON.
- · Data visualization using Plotly, Dash & Power BI.

Project: Build a recommendation system for active jobs depending on a CV input.

EDUCATION

WORKSHOPS - CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft - Data Engineer Associate - Ongoing

GCP - Generative AI for ML Engineers - Dec 2023

Microsoft - Data Analyst Associate - Aug 2023

D-ONE - BigQuery Essentials - Nov 2023

MASTER OF SCIENCE

<u>American College of Greece</u> - <u>Data Science</u> 2022 - 2024

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE

<u>University of Piraeus</u> - <u>Statistics & Insurance</u> 2011 - 2020

DATA SCIENCE BOOTCAMP 500 HOURS HANDS-ON

Big Blue Data Academy

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021

- Databases (SQL, MongoDB), APIs & Web Scraping
- EDA & Data Cleaning (Pandas, Numpy, Regex)
- Big Data (PySpark) & Cloud Computing (Amazon Web Services)
- Machine Learning (Scikit Learn) & Deep Learning (Keras)
- Visualization (Matplotlib, Seaborn, Dash, PowerBi)

DATA SCIENCE ACADEMY 100 HOURS HANDS-ON

Regeneration Academy by TITAN - Code. Hub

Dec 2020 - Jan 2021